

Ashish Patel Pune/India +91 7705047900 ashishpatel0720@gmail.com

aithub | in linkedin |

portfolio

SUMMARY

Experienced Big Data Engineer with 3.5+ years of total experience in BigData, Java, Scala, and Python seeking to apply my abilities to contribute and build something productive.

I love contributing to Open-source projects and a contributor to Apache Airflow and other Open source projects.

EXPERIENCE

WALMART GLOBAL TECH

Feb, 2021 - Present / Bangalore, India

SOFTWARE ENGINEER III (BIG DATA)

- Part of the supply chain technology team, and working on cutting edge forecasting solutions to enable the everyday low-cost philosophy of Walmart.
- Building High-Quality Scalable ETL Frameworks to build our Forecasting Pipelines.
- Migrated our On-Prem Hadoop Clusters to Google Cloud Platform as part of a strategic partnership with Google.
- Tech Stack Apache Spark, Java, PySpark, Apache Airflow, GCP DataProc, Bigguery, Astronomer

DEUTSCHE BANK

lulv. 2018 - Ian. 2021 / Pune. India

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Worked As a Big Data engineer in CIB division for Volcker Project.
- Developed Data pipelines for our Reporting ETL jobs, handling Terabytes of data every day across hundreds of Spark and Hadoop MapReduce jobs.
- Optimized End to End Pipeline execution time to comply with Regulatory SLA in accordance with new Volcker2.0 regulatory Norms.
- Developed Platform simplification for Informatica jobs using Java8 and Spring + Reactor Framework with Oracle Database.
- Tech Stack Apache Spark, Hadoop MapReduce, Hive, Impala, Beeline, Cloudera CDH, Java, Spring Framework, Spring Boot, Scala, Linux, GCP.

NIT, BHOPAL

Oct, 2017 - Feb, 2018 / Bhopal, India

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

- · Co-written "A Comparative Study of Music Recommendation Systems" with Prof. Rajesh Wadhvani.
- This paper describes different recommendation strategies and compares their practicality on mobile devices.
- Evaluated different Recommendation Strategies by training different ML models and evaluating them.
- ref https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8546852

CARWALE.COM

May, 2017 - Jul, 2017 / Mumbai, India

SUMMER INTERN

- Worked as Data Engineering Intern in the R&D division of CarWale.
- We developed CWBigQuery, which is a service that enables interactive analysis of massively large datasets stored in Cassandra Storage.
- It allows users to submit and schedule Spark Job, just using SQL like syntax using Spark SQL.
- This Project took inspiration from Google BigQuery but uses a completely different architecture, we have also created a web application which will provide an interface for users to log in and submit, schedule, and view results.
- Tech Stack Scala, Apache Spark, Cassandra, Python-Flask Framework

EDUCATION

NIT, BHOPAL 2014 - 2018

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY, COMPUTER SCIENCE & ENGINEERING

- Graduated in Computer Science and Engineering. **GGPA** 8.4/10
- Worked as Web developer in the Student Council and developed websites and tech infrastructure for College events.

I.P.S ACADEMY 2011 - 2013

HIGHER SECONDARY, SCIENCE & MATHEMATICS

Completed Higher Secondary with Physics, Chemistry, and Maths. Percentage - 90.2%

SKILLS _

PROGRAMMING Java | Scala | Python | C++ | Bash

Apache Spark | Hadoop MapReduce | Apache Airflow | Hive | Impala | Cloudera | Google Cloud **BIG DATA FRAMEWORKS**

Spring Framework | Oracle | MySql | Agile | DevOps **SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT**

> LANGUAGES Native: Hindi | Fluent: English

AWARDS AND RECOGNITION.

- Competed with 200+ teams and Won 3rd prize in Deutsche Bank's Global DataScience Competition Dabble.
 Won 2nd prize in Hackathon organized by Appointy Inc, https://github.com/pateash/appointy-hackathon
- Winner of Deutsche bank's excellence award.
- · Winner of Medhavi Chhatra Puruskar, given by MP State Government for excellent performance in State board exams.

EXTRA

- · Contributing to Apache Airflow, contributions https://github.com/pateash
- Working on Open source, CMD tool for developers, https://github.com/codingtools/cdt
- Writing Articles on Codebrace on Medium https://medium.com/codebrace, with over 70K+ reads so far.
- Created Opensource Regexplore, Intuitive Regex Checker https://regexplore.github.io